A Guide to the Francis Walker Gilmer Letters, 1818-1824
Library of Virginia
- Letter, 4 February 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Richmond, to Dabney Carr stating that Judge Fleming is dead. States that Henry St. George Tucker is heading to Richmond to push Carr for Fleming's spot on the Court of Appeals, and mentions other plans to push Carr for the position., 1 leaf, ALS.
- Letter, 4 February 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Richmond, to Dabney Carr stating that there is no confirmation of Judge Fleming's death., 1 leaf, ALS.
- Letter, 13 February 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Richmond, to Dabney Carr stating that Judge Fleming is not dead and commenting on his judgeship. Gilmer adds that Henry St. George Tucker is ill and that the Abbe Correa de Serra is dead., 1 leaf, ALS.
- Letter, 24 February 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Conference Room Ct. appeals, [Richmond], to Dabney Carr, announcing Carr's election to the Supreme Court of Appeals with vote tally., 1 leaf, ALS.
- Letter, 25 February 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Richmond, to Dabney Carr stating that the Court of Appeals will adjourn on 1 April. Gilmer asks after Carr's health and that of Judge Holmes. States that Henry St. George Tucker will succeed Carr to the chancellorship of the Winchester Superior Court of Chancery., 2 p., ALS.
- Letter, 5 March 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Richmond, to Dabney Carr stating that Henry St. George Tucker has been elected to succeed Carr. Gilmer recommends that Carr come to Richmond immediately., 1 leaf, ALS.
- Letter, 6 March 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Richmond, to Dabney Carr stating that Carr should come to Richmond immediately to qualify for his judgeship. Gilmer adds that the court will sit through the month, and that Henry St. George Tucker was elected to succeed him., 2 p., ALS.
- Letter, 3 May 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, Steam Boat, to Dabney Carr informing him that he had to leave without seeing Carr. Asks Carr to keep his mission a secret [recruiting professors for the University of Virginia]., 1 leaf, ALS.
- Letter, 17 September 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, London, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, stating that his return had been delayed because of summer vacations in England. Gilmer comments that he has employed four professors of the first caliber. Remarks on plans for the future and British lawyers. Gilmer states he expects to be back in February., 3 p., ALS.
- Letter, 14 November 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, New York, to Dabney Carr, Richmond, stating that his health has been destroyed by his return voyage from England, and commenting on his health. Gilmer has received no news from Virginia., 4 p., ALS.
- Letter, 4 December 1824, Francis Walker Gilmer, New York, to Dabney Carr commenting on his return voyage and stating that his illness is not known. Gilmer asks for news and comments on the introduction of robes into courts by Joseph Story., 3 p., ALS.